麦琪:不.我非常明白丧礼承办.
Maggie: No.I was very clear with the funeral director.
我需要在我父亲的丧礼上录象,而不是一位活的风琴师演奏选段.
I wanted tape tins at my father's funeral service,
不,我需要退款,我现在就要!
not a live organist playing selections from Fiddler on the Roof.
别挂.这很重要.
No I want a refund and I want it now.Hold on.This better be important.
本:是,它是.你把你的胸罩和衬衣放哪里了?
Ben: Yeah it is.Where do you keep your bras and slips?
麦琪:本,不管你动什么歪脑筋,我没那心情.
Maggie: Ben whatever kind of stupid stunt you are up to, I'm not in the mood.
本:好,那你的短衬裤呢?妈妈,这次和以前不一样.相信我.
Ben: Ok, how about your panties?Mum, this isn't like those other times.Trust me.
麦琪:出去!听着,底线是,
Maggie: Out!Look the bottom line is either you get a check in the mail today,
要么你今天把支票寄来,要么我让我律师打电话给你.而且……对不起,
or I'll have my attorney call you and ...excuse me, can you hold on?
你能等一下吗?有另外的电话进来了.喂,
I've got someone on the other line.Hello.Oh hi mum.
哦,嗨,妈妈.
Look, I've got someone on the other line.Can I...
我正在接另外一个电话,我可以……哦,妈妈,
Oh mum, I know its hard going through dad's things,
我知道整理爸爸的遗物是很伤心的,你能不能推迟一段时间?哦,
but can't you just put it off for a little while?
那很好,但是……杰森他已经有他需要的白带子了.你能不能稍等会儿,
Well that's very sweet, but...
妈妈?听着,要么你马上行动,
Jason has all the white belts he needsCan you hang on for a minute mum?
不然我告得你内裤都没有.妈妈,哦.
Look, either you get your act together, or I'll sue your pants off.Mum, oh
克莉丝:如果你只能带一双鞋,那是哪一双?
Chrissy: If you could only have one pair of shoes, which pair would they be?
麦琪:克莉丝,没见我在打电话吗?
Maggie: Chrissy, cant you see I'm on the phone?
克莉丝:啊哈.那么哪双?
Chrissy: Uh hu.So which pair?
麦琪:过会,克莉丝.
Maggie: Later Chrissy.
克莉丝:我建议平底鞋.你是个高女人.
Chrissy: I suggest the flats.You are a tall woman.
麦琪:克莉丝,进其它房间,别用你的废话来打扰我.
Maggie: Chrissy go into the other room and don't bother me with your nonsense.
克莉丝:激动了.真的激动了.
Chrissy: Boots.Definitely boots.
麦琪:听着,妈妈……
Maggie: Look mum...
开萝尔:那么克莉丝,哪一双?
Carol: So Chrissy, what pair?
克莉丝:我不知道,她骂了我一顿.
Chrissy: I don't know, she bit my head off.
迈克:在这,让我来试试.她总不会拒绝她的长子吧.哦,妈妈!
Mike: Here, let me give it a shot.She could never resist her first born.Oh mother!
杰森:好了,就这样,我们这就走.这是买吃的和应急用的现金,我们的航班……
Jason: Alright, here we go.Here's some cash for food and emergencies.Our flight information
开萝尔:嘘!爸爸,如果你还在说,她就发现那个旅程了.哎哟.
Carol: Shhhh!Dad, if you keep talking, she'll find out about the trip.Ow.
迈克:很好.赤脚跟我无关.爸爸,你为什么娶她?
Mike: Fine.Go barefoot for all I care.Dad, why did you marry her?
杰森:嗨,现在对你们的妈妈要理解一点.
Jason: Hey, a little bit of understanding towards your mother right now.
你外公埃迪去世才两个星期.
It's only been two weeks since your grandpa Ed died.
克莉丝:对于外公埃迪我也很伤心,
Chrissy: I'm sad about Grandpa Ed too,
但是我不会到处对每个人嚷嚷.
but I don't go around yelling at everybody.
杰森:行了.你们妈妈现在心里非常困惑和非常伤心.
Jason: Come on.Your mum's got some very confused and very sad feelings
你们知道吗?而且我知道这很难,
inside her right now.You know?
但是我需要表现的有点耐心.
And I know it's hard, but we have to show a little patience.
相互之间有些简单的仁慈.好吗?
Some simple kindness towards each other.Ok?
本:爸爸,我包好了,
Ben: Dad, I packed everything else you said,
按你说的,但是她没有带内衣.
but she's going without her underwear.
杰森:干的好,儿子.
Jason: Good work son.
麦琪:我正试图在权利范围内联系亨德森先生.对,我想再留个口信.你能不能告诉他,42年来,我父亲从来没有忘记付人寿保险金,即使意味着我没有舞鞋穿.不,我不是舞蹈演员.这就是为什么的原因.关键是我妈正等着这笔钱呢,下一个电话就该是我妈的律师了打来的,而且我要……他把我的电话挂了.
Maggie: I am trying to reach Mr.Henderson in claims.Yes I would like to leave another message.Would you please tell him that for forty two years my father never missed a payment on that life insurance policy, even if it meant that I had to go without tap shoes?No, I am not a dancer.And that is the reason why.The point being that my mother is waiting for that money and the next call you get is going to be from my mother's attorney and I'm going to...He hung up on me.
杰森:不.我挂断了你的电话.
Jason: No.I hung up on you.
麦琪:你!我怎么会嫁给你?
Maggie: You!Why did I marry you?
杰森:麦琪,
Jason: Maggie, if Mr.
如果亨德森先生想听口信的结尾,他只要简单地查阅昨天的电话.
Henderson wants to hear the end of that message then he can simple refer
或者前天的.
to yesterdays call.Or the day before.
麦琪:这个会真的好.
Maggie: This one was going to be really good.
杰森:你知道一些事情吗,麦琪?
Jason: You know something Maggie?
我觉得你现在只需要休息一下.
I think that you just need a little bit of a break.Stab at it.
刺一下.你在想什么呢?
What do you think?
麦琪:我在机场,在飞机的客舱里.
Maggie: I'm in an airport, on an airplane in coach section.
杰森:你不会比这还错了.
Jason: You couldn't be more wrong.
麦琪:杰森.
Maggie: Jason.
杰森:列车员,我们有一个卧铺.哦!
Jason: Conductor, we have a sleeper.Oh!
麦琪:杰森,我能让你摘掉这可笑的眼罩吗?
Maggie: Jason, can I please take off this ridiculous blindfold?
杰森:行,行.好的.是,是是!
Jason: Alright, alright.Ok.Ta daaa!
麦琪:哇,我们在飞机上.
Maggie: Wow.We are on an airplane.
杰森:是的.逃亡之旅.麦琪,相信我,小甜心,你需要.
Jason: Yes.A getaway trip.Maggie believe me sweetheart, you need it.
麦琪:亲爱的,非常美妙,但是现在我不能走.
Maggie: Honey, that's wonderful, but I can't go away right now.
杰森:是,你可以.当然.
Jason: Yes you can.Of course.
麦琪:好的,谁来照顾孩子?
Maggie: Ok, who's going to look after the kids?
杰森:迈克和开萝尔.
Jason: Mike and Carol.
麦琪:但是我得去……
Maggie: But I've got to....
杰森:麦琪,请!所有那些事情等我们从……某个地方回来之后再说.
Jason: Maggie please!All that stuff is still going to be there when we get backfrom....somewhere.
麦琪:可是我父亲的保险呢?而且怎么样……我们去哪儿?
Maggie: But what about my dad's insurance?And what about...Where are we going?
杰森:不,不.我不会告诉你的,除非你一道.
Jason: No.No.I am not going to tell you unless you come along.
飞机女乘务员:早上好.欢迎乘坐1265次航班,将直接飞往……
Air Stewardess: Good morning.And welcome aboard flight twelve sixty five with non stop service to...
杰森:喔,喔,喔!哦,哦,哦.对不起,我正带我太太进行一次特殊旅游,请你别提我们要去哪儿好吗?
Jason: Wo, wo, wo!Oh oh oh.Excuse me, I'm taking my wife on a
very special trip, so could we just not mention where we are going
飞机女乘务员:哦,
Air Stewardess: Oh, but this was going to be my first time to say where
可我这是第一次说我们去哪儿?
we were going.
杰森:那么,如果每个人都没意见的话,你也没意见?
Jason: Well, but if it's ok with everybody else, would it be ok with you?
飞机女乘务员:我可以.
Air Stewardess: I guess.
杰森:啊,对不起.我说这是我和我的太太的特别旅行.她是非常有魅力的金发碧眼女人,心情不太好.麦琪,麦琪 西维尔,站起来.别躲了.快点,麦琪.就是她.就是麦琪.
Jason: Ah, excuse me.I was saying that this is a very special trip for my wife and I.She's the very attractive blonde up there in the foul mood.Maggie.Maggie Seaver, stand up.Don't hide.Come on Maggie.There she is.That's Maggie.
每个人:(鼓掌)
Everyone: (applause)
杰森:还有,啊,
Jason: And uh, because this is a very special trip,
因为这是特殊旅行,对我们和我们的婚姻来说意义重大,
it would really mean a lot to us and to our marriage,
如果我们能不提及目的地.那样行吗?
if we could just not mention the destination.Would that be alright?
男人:驾驶员知道?
Man: Will the pilot know?
杰森:是的,他知道.
Jason: Yes he will.
男人:哦,好.
Man: Oh, ok.
杰森:啊哈,谢谢大家.我真感谢你们这样做,这对我们22年的婚姻意味着很多.
Jason: And uh, thank you all.I really appreciate that and it means a whole
lot for our marriage of twenty two years
每个人:啊!
Everyone: Ahhh!
男人2:对不起.我想让你知道,
Man 2: Excuse me.I want you to know that my wife and me have been married
我和我妻子结婚也是22年.
for twenty two years also.
杰森:哦,非常好.
Jason: Oh, that's nice.
男人2:想要交换?
Man 2: Want to swap?
麦琪:坐下.
Maggie: Sit down.
迈克:好啊,这星期将很疯狂.
Mike: Alright, this week is going to be a snap.
我是说,
I mean with all the money dad left us for emergencies,
爸爸给我们留下所有应急的钱,我只差20块就可以买个新的汽车立体声了.
I'm only twenty dollars short of a new car stereo.
开萝尔:迈克,你不明白的是,
Carol: Mike, what you don't realise is that this is a golden opportunity.
这是个绝好的机会.代替爸爸和妈妈的机会,把一切都做好.
A chance to take over from mum and dad and finally do the job right.
迈克:哦,开萝尔,你的方法听起来就像是工作.
Mike: Oh Carol, your way sounds like work.
开萝尔:我会让你简单点.我们是两个,
Carol: I'll make it easy for you.There are two of us and two of them.
他们也是两个.我说我们分开和征服.我当然负责那个成熟的.
I say we divide and conquer.I of course will get the mature one.
迈克:好,好,行.我照看本.
Mike: Ok.Ok fine.I'll take Ben.He's easier to handle anyway.
总之,他比较容易管理.他懂得美元的价值.
He understands the value of a dollar.
开萝尔:哦,你将成为好家长.你付钱让他听话.
Carol: Oh, some parent you would make.You pay him to behave.
迈克:不.他付给我钱不管他.
Mike: No.He pays me not to smack him around.
开萝尔:对于你,克莉丝,
Carol: And for you Chrissy, I've planned a healthy regiment of diet,
我已经准备了有益健康的菜谱,锻炼和有刺激性的游戏.克莉丝!
exercise and stimulating play.Chrissy!
迈克:听着,本.你不想有麻烦,
Mike: Look Ben.You don't want any problems, neither do I.
我也不想.好,
Ok, here's the deal: You give me twenty dollars,
这有个交易;你给我20块钱,你就没有麻烦了,我就不管你了.
you stay out of trouble and I leave you alone.
本:谢谢.很高兴你没有要五十块.
Ben: Thanks.Happy you didn't ask for fifty.
迈克:嘿,嘿,嘿,嘿嘿.这是平日.早晨10点.告诉你干什么了?
Mike: Hey, hey, hey hey.It's a weekday.Ten in the morning.What does that tell you?
本:放了?
Ben: Any Griffiths is on?
迈克:不,本.上学去.快点!告诉你,是10点30.
Mike: No Ben.School.Come on!And for you information, any Griffith sis ten thirty.
本:马克,你错过了这大片.
Ben: Mike, you are missing the big picture here.
妈妈爸爸那么忙,他们从来没有注意到我逃学.
Mum and dad got so busy, they didn't even notice that I didn't go.
很酷,呵?
Pretty cool, hu?
迈克:很好的主意,本.快点.上学去.
Mike: Nice try Bennie.Come on.Go to school.
本:也许这能使你改变主意.
Ben: Maybe this would change your mind.
迈克:不.快点,
Mike: Nope.Come on Ben.
本.如果爸爸妈妈发现我让你逃学,他们会杀了我.
If mum and dad find out that I let you skip school, they'll kill me.
本:但是……
Ben: But...
迈克:没有但是.上学去.
Mike: No buts.Go to school.
本:好的,好的.
Ben: Yeah yeah.
克莉丝:如果开萝尔问的话,你说你没有见到我.
Chrissy: If Carol asks, you didn't see me.
迈克:好.
Mike: Ok.
开萝尔:她去哪里了?
Carol: Which way did she go?
迈克:哦,是不是我们的小女儿有点麻烦了?
Mike: Oh, are we having a little problem with our daughter?
开萝尔:哦,好象本的事情一切顺利!
Carol: Oh like things are going so smoothly with Ben!
迈克:是的.是片蛋糕,开萝尔.行了.
Mike: They are.It's a piece of cake carol.Come on.
本和我有相同的理解.我们一起辩论.他尊重我.
Bennie and I have an understanding.We reason together.He respects me.
开萝尔:我明白了.所以本开你的车呢?
Carol: I see.So that's why he's driving off in your car?
迈克:嗨!
Mike: Hey!
空中小姐:这是你的迈代鸡尾酒和你的澳大利亚坚果.
Air Hostess: Here's your MaiTai and your Macadamia nuts.
你想点我们哪种阿罗哈岛的风味晚餐?
Now which of the Low Ho Island dinners would you like to order?
杰森:我们不饿.
Jason: We're not hungry.
麦琪:亲爱的,这不是她的错.
Maggie: Honey, it's not her fault.She's paid to give us lays.
付钱给她提供服务的.还有,我真不知道我们要去哪儿?
Besides, I don't have Don Ho of a clue where we are going.
迈克:是的,长官.
Mike: Yes officer.It's a convertible with license plate number.....Forget it.
这是敞篷车,车牌号是……算了吧.他来了.
It just walked in.
本:碰巧.
Ben: It just happened.
迈克:哦,碰巧.
Mike: Oh, it happened.
你正好碰巧没有锁我的车门,
You just happened to unlock my car door,
发动车子,开出了车道!
start the car and drive out the drive way!
本:那,我正要把车开回车道,但是我迷路了.
Mike: Oh oh.Tell me Mr., how do you get lost in a driveway.
迈克:哦哦.告诉我先生,你怎么在车道上迷路的?
Ben: Well I was just going to drive it back and forth in the driveway, but I got lost.
本:我没有地图,一旦你上了收费公路,你就得一直开.
Ben: Well I didn't have a map and once you get on that turnpike, you've got to keep going.
迈克:你,你,你上了收费公路?
Mike: You, you, you got in the turnpike?
本:是的.直到警察把我停下.
Ben: Yeah.Until the policeman stopped me.
迈克:警察!
Mike: The policeman!
本:是,你有一张罚单.
Ben: Yeah, you got a ticket.
迈克:什么!
Mike: What!
本:他不会把这个给我的.我没有驾照.我借用了你的.
Ben: Well he couldn't give it to me.I don't have a license.I borrowed yours.
迈克:够了.你被关禁闭了,先生.你听我说了吗?回你的房间去.
Mike: That's it.You are grounded Mr.You hear me?Go to your room.
本:你认为你能管得了我吗?好,我走.
Ben: You think you can make me?Ok, I'll go.
但是只是因为反正我总是要回房间的.哦,我被关禁闭了.
But only because I was going to anyway.Oooh, I'm grounded.
克莉丝:迈克,我需要帮忙.开萝尔有精神病.
Chrissy: Mike, I need help.Carol's insane.
迈克:哈,那没人可以帮忙.
Mike: Yeah well no one can help.
克莉丝:迈克,她教我拉丁文,可我连英语还不太好?
Chrissy: Mike, she's teaching me Latin and I'm not too good with English yet.
开萝尔:克莉丝.好了,好了,
Carol: Chrissy, Quo Vardis.Now now Chrissy.
克莉丝.你知道,到三点一刻才能自由活动.
You know that free play isn't till three fifteen.
迈克:行了,开萝尔.给孩子片刻休息时间.
Mike: Come on Carol.Give the kid a break.
Carol: Chrissy, please translate the following: Omnis gallea est divisea impart est tres omnibus
麦琪:这回我知道了.纽约.
Maggie: I got it this time.New York City.
杰森:你能停止吗?
Jason: Would you stop it.
麦琪:哦,亲爱的,
Maggie: Oh honey, if it's any consolation,
如果这是任何安慰的话,我不知道我们在夏威夷哪个岛上.
I don't know which island in Hawaii we are on.
杰森:我再不令你惊讶了.
Jason: I'm never surprising you again.
麦琪:我现在拿下我的眼罩了.
Maggie: I'm taking my mask off now.
杰森:为什么,你已经知道我们在什么地方.
Jason: Why, you already know where we are.
麦琪:我们坐爱斯基摩小艇?
Maggie: We are going Kayaking?
杰森:不,麦琪,我们去野营.
Jason: No Maggie, we are going camping.
麦琪:真的?
Maggie: Really!
杰森:是的.
Jason: Yeah.
麦琪:我们一直谈论这个话题.两个海滩流浪人在天堂.
Maggie: We always talked about this.Two beach bums in paradise.
杰森:好像我们拥有整个岛屿一样.
Jason: It's like we have the whole island to ourselves.
麦琪:哦(哭),哦,杰森.
Maggie: Oh (Crying) Oh Jason.
杰森:亲爱的,怎么了?
Jason: Honey, what's wrong.
麦琪:一切.
Maggie: Everything.
杰森:亲爱的.
Jason: Honey.
麦琪:好,我很好.我们走吧.
Maggie: Ok, I'm fine.Let's go.
杰森:但是啊,你在哭.
Jason: But uh, you were crying.
麦琪:我知道.对不起.我控制不住.快点,我们去开心,开心,开心.
Maggie: I know.I'm sorry.I got carried away.Come on, let's have fun fun fun.
杰森:小甜心,悲伤没什么的.
Jason: Sweetheart, it's alright to grieve.
麦琪:是的,医生.
Maggie: Yes doctor.
杰森:你知道我还记得我父亲什么时候去世.
Jason: You know I remember when my dad died.
麦琪:亲爱的,我记得.我在那.
Maggie: Honey, I remember.I was there.
杰森:麦琪,你不要隐藏自己的情绪.
Jason: Maggie, you can't hide your feelings.
麦琪:杰森,我看上去像不开心的人?
Maggie: Jason, do I look like an unhappy person?
杰森:是的.
Jason: Yeah.
麦琪:那我没有.
Maggie: Well I'm not.
杰森:我不相信你.
Jason: I don't believe you.
麦琪:杰森,我们从很远来飞到夏威夷.难道我们不能至少玩的开心吗?
Maggie: Jason, we have flown all the way to Hawaii.Can't we at least enjoy it?
杰森:当然,小甜心.听着,
Jason: Of course sweetheart.
我想让你知道,如果你遇到什么根本烦心的事,
Look I want you to know if there is anything at all bothering you, anything,
任何事情,请,我需要你对我说?
please I want you to talk to me.
麦琪:你这么好.我消受不起.
Maggie: Will you quit being so nice.I don't deserve it.
杰森:你消受不起是什么意思呀?
Jason: What do you mean you don't deserve it?
麦琪:没什么,没什么.开吧.
Maggie: Nothing, nothing.Just drive.
杰森:如果我让你把对你爸的感情隐藏起来,
Jason: I'd be doing you a disservice if I let you duck the feelings you've
那我就是对你伤害.
been having about your dad.
麦琪:我不会感觉心那我应该有的感觉.好吗?
Maggie: I'm not feeling what I should be feeling.Ok?
本:我们就吃这个?这就像狗嘴里吐出来的东西.
Ben: We are supposed to eat this?It looks like something a dog coughed up.
克莉丝:我订了比萨饼.
Chrissy: I'm ordering pizza.
迈克:嘿,听着.
Mike: Hey look.I spent the last two hours boiling this garbage.
我花了差不多两个小时来煮这垃圾.现在谁也别走,直到吃完最后一片牛肝.
Now nobody leaves until every last liver burger is gone.
本:好吧.
Ben: Ok.
迈克:嗨.
Mike: Hey.
本:我们需要比萨上加干酪和意大利辣香肠?
Ben: We want extra cheese and pepperoni on that pizza?
迈克:好了,你这次太过分了.你不准打电话,直到爸爸妈妈回来,.
Mike: Alright pal you have gone too far this time.No more telephone for you until mum and dad get home.
本:我没有必要忍受这些.我比你高.
Ben: I don't have to put up with this.I'm taller than you.
开萝尔:迈克,他在考验你.你必须给他定规矩.
Carol: Mike, he's testing you.You have to draw the line.
克莉丝:或者培养.
Chrissy: Or grow.
克莉丝:呀!本!本,本!
Chrissy: Yeah!Ben!Ben Ben!
本:瞧你的肘.
Ben: Watch your elbows.
迈克:伤我比伤你多的多.总有一天你会为此感谢我.
Mike: This is hurting me a lot more than it's hurting you.One day you are going to thank me for this.
本:你说话像妈妈
Ben: You sound just like mum.
迈克:哦,是的.妈妈也这么做?呀,你觉得怎么样?
Mike: Oh yeah.Well does mum do this?Yeah, how do you like that hu?
本:你不能压我整夜.
Ben: You can't pin me down all night long.
迈克:你是对的.开萝尔,给我拿根绳子.
Mike: You are right.Carol, bring me a rope.
杰森:亲爱的,晚餐就绪.开始了.坐在这里,放下包袱.
Jason: Honey, dinner is ready.Come on.Sit over here and take a load off.
麦琪:对不起,我发火了.
Maggie: I'm sorry I got upset.
杰森:哪.是我应该道歉,不是你.
Jason: Na.It's me who should apologise, not you.
麦琪:为什么?
Maggie: What for?
杰森:因为没带内衣来.这次和前几次不同.这次是个诚实的错误.
Jason: For not bringing underwear.This wasn't like the other times.This was an honest mistake.
麦琪:那很甜蜜,但是不用担心.我穿你的.我们晚饭吃什么?
Maggie: Well that's very sweet, but don't worry.I'm wearing yours.What is for dinner
杰森:野蘑菇.
Jason: Marshmallows.
麦琪:就这?
Maggie: That's it?
杰森:对不起,今天我有点心烦意乱.我没有去市场.
Jason: I'm sorry, I was a little distracted today.I didn't get to the market.
麦琪:哦,我毁掉了我们整个假期.是吗?
Maggie: Oh.I've ruined our whole vacation.Haven't I?
杰森:没有.我找到了许多野蘑菇.
Jason: Na.I got lots of marshmallows.
麦琪:记得上次我们去野营,我们过的有多糟吗?
Maggie: Remember what a terrible time we had the last time we went camping?
杰森:我们玩儿的很开心.
Jason: We had a great time.
麦琪:不,不,不.
Maggie: No no no.
我说的是,当本,迈克和开萝尔小的时候,
I'm talking about when Ben and Mike and Carol were babies and Mike had
迈克腹泻,而且下雨,什么都都是湿透的.
diarrhea and it rained and everything got all wet.
杰森:我说的是同样的旅行.
Jason: I'm talking about the same trip.
麦琪:那次野营有什么好的?
Maggie: Well what was so nice about that?
杰森:我们在一起,麦琪.当时看着你和迈克,真是甜蜜.
Jason: We were together Maggie.And it was so sweet watching you with Mike.
在你的怀里摇着他,直到他入睡.可他从来不睡.
Rocking him in your arms until he fell asleep.Which he never did.
麦琪:我已经都忘了这所有一切.难道不就是上星期吗?
Maggie: I'd forgotten all about that.Wasn't it just last week?
杰森:不.上星期你摇的是我.
Jason: No.That was me you rocked last week.
麦琪:现在跟他在一起一分钟就是幸运了.
Maggie: I'd be lucky to get a minute with him nowadays.
杰森:他们一下子长大了,是吗?
Jason: They grow up in a hurry, don't they?
麦琪:你知道我们的口气像谁呀?我们的口气就像我们父母的说话口气.
Maggie: You know how we sound like?We sound like our parents talking.
杰森:我想能使我高兴的是,总有这么一天,
Jason: Well the eon enjoy that I get in all this is that one day,
迈克,开萝尔和本,
Mike and Carol and Ben and Chrissy are all going to be sitting around
还有克莉丝,也会这样坐在篝火旁,
a campfire like this,
突然发现,他们说话的语气也像老不中用的我们一样.
suddenly dumbstruck at the very thought that they are sounding like old
哈哈哈.你好吗?
irrelevant us.Ha ha ha.You ok?
麦琪:我想告诉你,今天我说我有一种不该有的感觉是什么意思?
Maggie: I want to tell you what I meant today when I said I wasn't feeling the right feelings.
杰森:啊哈.好的.
Jason: Uh hu.Ok.
麦琪:你知道他葬礼那天吗?当我看见爸爸在棺材里,
Maggie: You now the day of his funeral?
我想,我想,多可惜呀.
When I saw daddy there in that coffin, I thought, I thought what a shame.
杰森:当然了,小甜心.他是你父亲.
Jason: Of course sweetheart.He's your father.
麦琪:不,那不是我想说的.我想……
Maggie: No that's not what I mean.I thought...
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
麦琪:我想到的是为了抚养我,他付出的劳动和照料,
Maggie: Well I thought about all the work and the care he's put into raising
而最后我……
me and in the end I...
杰森:什么,亲爱的?
Jason: What honey?
麦琪:可怕的想法.
Maggie: It's a horrible thought.
杰森:说吧.
Jason: Well just say it.
麦琪:我不再需要他了.我是说我确实是非常和真诚地爱他,
Maggie: I didn't need him anymore.
想念他.
I mean sure I loved him and I miss him terribly but honestly.
他占据我生命中多大的部分呢?我是说,
How much a part of my life was he?
我从来没听过他的建议.
I mean, I never listened to his advice.His opinions were always nutty.
他的意见通常是废话.有时干脆不理他.
Sometimes it was just easier to ignore him.
我是说,
I mean god help me,
上帝帮助我,我爱看他感恩节和孩子在一起的样子.
I loved it when he sat at the kids table on thanksgiving.
杰森:亲爱的,没有理由感到内疚.
Jason: Honey, that's no reason to feel guilty.That's just the way things work.
生活就是这样的.
Like we were saying about mike when he was a little baby.
就像我们说说迈克,当他小的时候.
How he needed every word you had to say.
你说的哪一句话他都听.
Now we've created someone who doesn't listen to anything we say.
现在我们培养了一个我们说什么都不听的孩子.我们做得很好.
We've done our job well.
麦琪:哦,杰森.你不明白?
Maggie: Oh Jason.Don't you see?One day it's going to be our turn.
有一天会轮到我们.我是说,
I mean some day we'll die and one of our kids will be sitting here telling
我们某天也会死的,我们的孩子也会坐在这儿告诉别人,你和我对他们的生活也不重要.
someone about how you and I weren't important to their lives either.
我是说毕竟我们投入了所有的心血.毕竟那些瓶瓶罐罐,那些脏尿布,
I mean after all the work we've put in.
生日,还有假期.
After all the bottles and the dirty diapers and the birthdays and the
我是说,这些都不值得一提.有什么意义?
vacations.I mean, they won't mean a thing.What's the point?
杰森:如果你难过的是这个,而不光是你爸.
Jason: If that's what's bothering you, then it's not just your dad.
麦琪:如果可爱的照料我的人得到的是像我这样的,
Maggie: If that sweet caring man ended up with someone like me,
我还有什么盼头.
what do I have to hope for?
杰森:你是不是太悲观了点?
Jason: Aren't you being just a little pessimistic?
麦琪:我是?
Maggie: Am I?
杰森:我说是的,麦琪.我看你给孩子的影响多得很.迈克的魅力,
Jason: I mean it Maggie.Come on.You influence your kids in a thousand ways.
开萝尔的聪明,克莉丝的可爱,本的……身高.
Mike's charm and Carol's brains and Chrissie's cuteness and Ben's....height.
麦琪:这一点也不烦你.是吗?
Maggie: This doesn't bother you at all.Does it?
杰森:不.不.
Jason: No.No.
麦琪:杰森,我真的感到很苦恼.
Maggie: Jason, that really ticks me off.
杰森:你注意到我烤野蘑菇的方法吗?
Jason: Have you ever noticed the way I toast a marshmallow?
麦琪:是的,这也让我感到很烦恼.
Maggie: Yeah and that really ticks me off too.
杰森:我烤着,麦琪,很棒.
Jason: I do it, Maggie, perfect.All nice and even and brown on all sides.
我烤得很好很均匀,四面都是金黄的.你知道还有谁这样烤蘑菇吗?
You know who else toasts his marshmallows that way?
麦琪:不.
Maggie: No.
杰森:我爸爸.我也是几年以前才意识到.
Jason: My dad.I noticed that just a couple of years ago.
从这件小事情上,
And that one small connection Maggie,
麦琪,使得我认识到我父亲对我的影响无处不在.
made me see that my dad influenced me in countless ways.
连我自己也想不到的方面.
Ways I cant even imagine.
这就像你父亲对你的影响,以及我们对孩子们的影响一样.
Just like your dad influenced you and just like we will influence our kids.
麦琪:你知道,我爸爸如果听到你这样说话会怎么说?
Maggie: You know what my dad would say if he heard you talking like this?
杰森:不.但我肯定你知道.
Jason: No.But I'm sure you do.
麦琪:我希望我能确定.
Maggie: I wish I could be sure.
迈克:别动,本!
Mike: Freeze Ben!
开萝尔:你睡在这儿?
Carol: You slept down here?
迈克:睡觉!谁睡觉了?
Mike: Sleep!Who slept?
我在站岗,
I've been standing guard so the little weasel wouldn't sneak out.
那样这混蛋就溜不出去.克莉丝在哪?
Where's Chrissy?
开萝尔:没事.她把自己锁在她房间里.
Carol: Safe.She's locked in her room.
迈克:好.你也把她锁房里了?
Mike: Good.You locked her up too?
开萝尔:不是.她把自己锁进去的.
Carol: No.She locked herself in.
迈克:对不起,我得放本出来上学去.
Mike: Well I'm just sorry I've got to let Bennie out for school.
开萝尔:我希望你得把窗户钉死,这样他就不能顺着水管子爬下来了.
Carol: Well I hope you nailed his window shut so he didn't climb down the trellis.
迈克:哦!
Mike: Oh!
出租车司机:走啦.计价器工作.
Taxi driver: Let's go.Meters running.
开萝尔:我们没有叫出租车.
Carol: We didn't order a cab.
出租车司机:克莉丝 西维尔.送到公园路幼儿园.
Taxi Driver: Chrissy Seaver.Drop off at Parkway preschool.
克莉丝:好呀.我们走.
Chrissy: That's right.Let's go.
开萝尔:你叫了出租车?
Carol: You called a cab?Why in the world did you do that?
你究竟为什么要这样做?
I drive you to preschool.
我送你去幼儿园.出租车司机可不会给你唱歌,
A cab driver is not going to sing you songs and he's not going to tell
也不会给你讲个人胜利的故事.
you personal victory stories.
克莉丝:我知道.我查过.我们走.
Chrissy: I know.I checked.Let's go!
本:嗨,妈妈.我回家了.
Ben: Hi mum.I'm home.
开萝尔:瞧,真是抱歉,肯定弄错了.她才四岁.
Carol: Look, I am really sorry, but this has been a mistake.She is only four years old.
迈克:好.我要去杀了他.你!
Mike: Alright.I'm going to kill him.You!
出租车司机:你们俩结婚太早.
Taxi Driver: You kids married too young!
本:你又有一张罚单,迈克.
Ben: You got another ticket Mike.
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
本:是的.你很幸运,被你撞的车的司机,他没要钱.
Ben: Yeah.You are lucky the driver of the car you hit didn't press charges.
迈克:好啊,你要付的比钱多的多.
Mike: Alright, you are going to pay a lot more than money pal.
本:你干什么?哇.
Ben: What are you doing?Ow.
迈克:我要教训教训你.你已经品尝过了.
Mike: I'm coming for you.You have had it.
克莉丝:不!
Chrissy: No!
所有孩子:(尖叫和打架)
All kids: (Screaming and fighting)
杰森:嗨嗨!
Jason: Hey.Hey!
迈克:欢迎回家,
Mike: Welcome home.
杰森:松开他.
Jason: Let him go.
克莉丝:妈咪!我真高兴见到你.
Chrissy: Mummy!Am I glad to see you?
开萝尔:妈妈,真高兴你这么早回来.
Carol: Mum, I am so glad you are home early.
麦琪:天堂并没有吹嘘的那么好.
Maggie: Well paradise wasn't all it's cracked up to be.
杰森:谁来帮我拎这些包?
Jason: Anybody want to help me with the bags?
克莉丝:开萝尔想要害我.还有迈克给我们吃有毒的牛肝.
Chrissy: Carol tried to maul me.And Mike tried to give us liver poisoning.
开萝尔:妈妈,我不知道你怎么受得了她.尤其是在你给我这样好的工作.
Carol: Mum, I don't know who you put up with her.Especially after you did such a good job with me.
本:绳子印子,妈妈.
Ben: Rope burns mum.Rope burns.Need I say more?
绳子印子.还要我再说吗?可他却说,
And then he even told me that this was hurting him more than it was hurting
他这样做却比我更受伤,总有一天我会感谢他的.
me and some day I'd thank him for it.
麦琪:那是我说的.
Maggie: That's what I say.
本:是的.他疯了.
Ben: Yeah.He's gone nuts.
麦琪:迈克,你说这话了?
Maggie: Mike, did you say that?
迈克:瞧,我张开嘴巴,它就出来了.
Mike: Look, I opened my mouth and it came out.
麦琪:他就出来?
Maggie: It just came out?
迈克:是呀.你放那的.
Mike: Yeah.Well you put it there.
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: Yeah.
本:还有坏消息,妈妈.
Ben: More bad news mum.Mike even tried to charge me money to behave.Yeah.
迈克甚至向我要钱来听话.是的.我也很震惊.
I was shocked too.
麦琪:我不在乎.
Maggie: I don't care.
克莉丝:还有更糟的,开萝尔的那些奋斗故事,
Chrissy: And worse than that,
我都听得完全不想听了.
Carol's victory stories have made me want to give up completely.
麦琪:哦,真美妙.
Maggie: Oh that's wonderful.
开萝尔:妈妈,我不知道你怎么受得了他们.我是说总有一天他们会认识到你们多伟大,自己是多么烂.
麦琪:哦,开萝尔.有时候你说的是最甜蜜的话了.
00:22:18,500
Carol: Mum, I don't know how you put up with any of them.I mean one day they are going to realise how great you are and what festering scum they are. Maggie: Oh Carol.Sometimes you say the sweetest things.